<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gokul Dinesh</title>
    <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gokul Dinesh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:36:03 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cyberflaw.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Binge Watch</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/binge-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:36:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/binge-watch/</guid>
      <description>History Link to heading This idea originated during the lockdown period. One of my friends and I were talking and suddenly he told that it would be nice if we all could see a movie together, at the same time. And this was the idea behind Binge Watch.
How it works Link to heading It asks all the users to download and load a video file into memory. After everyone is finished loading, everyone&amp;rsquo;s media controls for the HTML video element (except volume) will be linked by WebSockets (Socket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Scraper Bots</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/web-scrapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:06:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/web-scrapers/</guid>
      <description>History Link to heading This was the very first few proper programs I wrote. Before this, I only knew programming concepts. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to use these concepts in real-world applications. These few scripts brought me into programming.
Current State Link to heading The spirits consist a Youtube scraper and Billboard Hot 100 Scraper. The repo is really messy, but it&amp;rsquo;ll always hold a special place in my heart</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchro Protocol</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/synchro-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:06:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/synchro-protocol/</guid>
      <description>History Link to heading This is an ongoing project as a part of the Senior Year project. This protocol will be used for real-time audio transmission/streaming over TCP
How it works Link to heading It&amp;rsquo;s a network protocol with many parts left to decide. We have to build and benchmark and find the optimal sizes of packets and segments in the packets. This protocol sits inside the TCP data part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood Bank</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/blood-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:06:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/blood-bank/</guid>
      <description>History Link to heading I was asked to create a blood bank website for our campus.
How its build Link to heading Its build on the MERN Stack
Current State Link to heading It was deployed in Heroku. But as the free tier was removed, the project remained untouched</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coordinox - Pointing Device</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/coordinox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:06:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/coordinox/</guid>
      <description>History Link to heading This project was built as a part of the Mini Project for the even semester of Junior year. Upon searching for ideas, we came across a device that can identify gestures and read sign language. We modified that idea and thought&amp;hellip;
We have projectors in our classes right, why do teachers have to use a mouse or trackpad to move the cursor? Why can&amp;rsquo;t we build something that can make a device that can make the projection like a touch screen or a smart classroom?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid Focus</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/covid-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:06:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/covid-focus/</guid>
      <description>History Link to heading This project was handed over to us by one of our professors. We were asked to create a Covid tracker for a Panchayat. We used React.js to build the front end, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t involve too much. I was handling the backend and database for the project. I used Node.js for creating the REST API and Postgresql as the database for the tracker
Why Node.js and Postgresql Link to heading I used *Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rendering Engine</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/rendering-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:05:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/rendering-engine/</guid>
      <description>History Link to heading It would be a lie if I say that I was never into game development, even my first ever programming-ish experience was making a Game in Game Maker Engine way back. When I was randomly scrolling through Youtube one day, if I remember correctly it was during the launch of PS5 and the Unreal Engine Demo, a dude named The Cherno popped up on my feed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voxel Graphic Engine</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/voxel-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:05:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/voxel-engine/</guid>
      <description>History Link to heading This project is a result of the previous OpenGL rendering engine I build using C++. Since I learned Rust I was always facinated by it&amp;rsquo;s type system and its borrow checker. I wanted to rewrite the rendering engine in Rust an wanted to add a lot more abstraction layers on top.
Why I&amp;rsquo;m building this Link to heading I wish to recreate Minecraft one day, as it was one of the most ground breaking game at it&amp;rsquo;s time and still is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IEEE SB GECT Club Website</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/ieee-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:05:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/ieee-website/</guid>
      <description>History Link to heading This website is built for the IEEE Student Branch of Government Engineering College Thrissur. I was selected for the Web Masters team for IEEE SB GECT 2021, and our team was assigned to build a static website for the club. It&amp;rsquo;s built using the Gatsby framework
Why Gatsby.Js Link to heading Gatsby was used due to a specific condition we are given during the assignment of the work; we had to make the website static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rumble - Chat Application</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/rumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:03:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/project/rumble/</guid>
      <description>History Link to heading I started this project as a part of the Career Development Program, by TinkerHub. I was qualified into the final stage and I was asked to do either one of the tasks
Create a Google Keeps clone Create a Real-Time Chat application with Authentication So from the title it&amp;rsquo;s evident which path I chose.
Why Rust? Link to heading This was my very first attempt to learn Rust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contacts</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:13:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email : dev.gokuldinesh@gmail.com
GitHub : github.com/CyberFlaw
LinkedIn : linkedin.com/in/cyberflaw
Instagram : instagram.com/cyber.flaw
Contact Number : +91 8921760744</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:13:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started my Developer journey around my fresher year of my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree. Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve played in a wide variety of areas. These include Full Stack Web Development, Mobile Development, Computer Graphics, Cloud Computing, DevOps, and so on. Some of the documented side projects I&amp;rsquo;ve done are listed below
Chat Application : Build on Next.Js as Frontend and Rust (Actix Web) as Backend
IEEE SB GECT Club Website : Build on Gatsby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://cyberflaw.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:12:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyberflaw.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Gokul Dinesh, a Full Stack Software Engineer and a Systems Developer, currently in Senior year of B.Tech Computer Science Engineering, who is open to opportunities and adventures. I&amp;rsquo;m currently based in Kerala, India. I&amp;rsquo;m a huge advocate for free and open-source learning and I&amp;rsquo;m currently into systems development, computer graphics and kernels. I&amp;rsquo;ve also dabbled in Cloud and DevOps for a few side projects.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently looking for Internships in Backend Development, Cloud Engineering, Systems Development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
